Like I said, welcome brothers and
sisters to another Wednesday question
and answer where we open up with the ten
commandments that God commanded the
whole world to keep. Brother James.
>> Yes, sir. And God spake all these words,
saying, I am the Lord thy God, which
have brought thee out of the land of
Egypt, out of the house of bondage. Thou
shalt have no other gods before me. Thou
shalt not make unto thee any graven
image, or any likeness of anything that
is in heaven above, or that is in the
earth beneath, or that is in the water
under the earth. Thou shalt not bow down
thyself to them, nor serve them. For I,
the Lord thy God, am a jealous God,
visiting the iniquity of the fathers
upon the children unto the third and
fourth generation of them that hate me,
and showing mercy unto thousands of them
that love me, and keep my commandments.
Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord
thy God in vain. For the Lord will not
hold him guiltless that taketh his name
in vain. Remember the Sabbath day to
keep it holy. Sixth day shalt thou
labor, and do all thy work, but the
seventh day is the Sabbath of the Lord
thy God. In it thou shalt not do any
work, thou, nor thy son, nor thy
daughter, thy man's servant, nor thy
maidervant, nor thy cattle, nor thy
stranger that is within thy gates. For
in six days the Lord made heaven and
earth, the sea, and all that in them is,
and restth the seventh day. Wherefore
the Lord blessed the Sabbath day, and
hollowed it. Honor thy father and thy
mother, that thy days may be long upon
the land, which the Lord thy God giveth
thee. Thou shalt not kill. Thou shalt
not commit adultery. Thou shalt not
steal. Thou shalt not bear false witness
against thy neighbor. Thou shalt not
covet thy neighbor's house. Thou shalt
not covet thy neighbor's wife, nor as
man's servant, nor as maid servant, nor
as ox, nor as ash, nor anything that is
thy neighbors. I read Exodus 20:es 1-1
17. May the Lord add a blessing to the
reading of this word. In Jesus name we
pray. Amen.
>> Amen.
And here on question and answer, you can
ask us a question and we'll answer it
according to the King James Bible. And
if we cannot find the answer, we will
seek further counsel to bring you an
answer at a later time. The questions we
will not answer are the vague as well as
the long scripture questions and
questions of debate. We are not here to
debate. We are here to spread the true
gospel of Jesus. So please be as direct
as possible with your questions so we
can be as direct as possible with our
answers. Either of the King James Bible
nor the Bibles or books will be
acknowledged on this program. And we
also ask you to remember that this is a
live stream. So feel free to send in
your questions that pertain to
everlasting life. We're just asking that
you keep them to a two scripture
maximum. Let me introduce to you the
family that's on the panel this evening.
You got brother Dre.
>> Good evening.
>> Brother Julius.
>> Good evening everybody.
>> Brother Jerome, praise and peace.
>> Brother James,
>> good evening everyone. Sister Deborah,
>> good evening.
>> Brother Sean,
>> And we have the guest caller with us.
And I'm Brother Cornell. Sister Deborah,
what is our first question of the
evening?
>> Uh, yes, there are several held over
questions that will be answered first
before getting into tonight's Q&A.
Marcelino Reed asks, "As Israel, do we
have the rights of the firstborn?"
>> All right. As Israel, do we have the
rights of the firstborn? Brother Dre,
what you say?
>> Yes, sir. Let's go over to Exodus 4 and
we going to read verse 22 there. Exodus
4 and 22.
See what the Bible says. Go ahead,
brother. When you get it, read it.
And thou shalt say unto Pharaoh, thus
sayeth the Lord, Israel is my son, even
my firstborn. So, Israel is the Lord's
firstborn. Now, let's go over to Romans
9. Romans nine, we going to read verses
1-4. Romans 9 1-4.
>> Go ahead when you get it.
>> Well, just just read four. Just read.
>> Yeah. Romans 9 and4 says, "Who are
Israelites to whom pertainth the
adoption and the glory and the covenants
and the giving of the law and the
service of God and the promises?"
>> Read five.
>> Whose are the fathers and of whom are
cons as concerning the flesh Christ came
who is over all God bless forever. Amen.
So all these things pertain to Israel.
But let's directly answer your question.
Let's go over to Isaiah 61. Isaiah 61.
We going to read verses
6 and 7. Isaiah 61 6 and 7. Go ahead
when you get it, brother. But ye shall
be named the priest of the Lord. Men
shall call you the ministers of our God.
Ye shall eat the riches of the Gentiles,
and in their glory shall ye boast
yourselves.
>> For your shame ye shall have double, and
for confusion they shall rejoice in
their portion. Therefore, in their land
they shall possess possess the double.
Everlasting joy shall be unto them.
>> One more place, let's go to Zechariah 9
and read verse 12. Zechariah 9 and 12.
Go ahead when you get it, bro.
>> Zechariah 9 and verse 12 says, "Turn you
to the stronghold, ye prisoners of hope.
Even today do I declare that I will
render double unto thee."
>> Because that's the portion of the
firstborn, double. That's all I got.
>> All right. Thank you for that, brother.
I hope that answered that question as we
move on to our next
>> next one. Brent Bratz says, "I need help
with how the order of man works. Isn't
it God, man, woman, then kids?" My
friend said, "If the man dies, the
inheritance go to his sons, and the sons
take care of the widow." Are they
correct?
All right, brother Julius, what's the
order?
>> Uh, let's go to 1 Corinthians the 11th
chapter.
And you got the order almost right. You
missed one person. You said God, that's
the father. You didn't mention Jesus.
1 Corinthians James 11, pick this up at
verse 1 and then we're going to jump
down to verse three.
1 Corinthians 11:1 says, "Be ye
followers of me, even as I also am of
Christ."
>> So now there's Jesus right there, right?
Skip now to verse three. Go ahead.
>> But I would have you know that the head
of every man is Christ.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And the and the head of the woman is the
man, and the head of Christ is God.
>> And then the children are an addition to
the family. Okay. So now that's the
order of things. The father, the son,
man, the woman, and then the children.
Let's go to 1 Timothy the 5th chapter.
Because in today's society, you have to
have if you have a life insurance
policy, back in ancient days, it was
automatically uh unless something
happened, you could forfeit that
inheritance. But uh in today's society
you have to have uh um life insurance
policy and you have to have beneficiary
to make it official beneficiaries. Okay.
Who you want to leave the inheritance to
in this uh corrupt society. First
Timothy 5 and James please read verses
three and four.
>> Okay.
>> When you get it.
Honor widows that are widows indeed.
>> Now if the husband dies, you honor the
widow. How? Verse four.
>> But if any widow have children or
nephews, let them learn first to show
piety at home.
>> You take care of home first. You got to
take somebody got to take care of mama.
Go ahead.
>> And to requite their parents,
>> right? But that is you honor and you
respect your parents. Take care of mama.
Take care of daddy. Go ahead.
>> For that is good and acceptable before
God.
>> Now verse eight. Go ahead.
>> But if any provide not for his own,
especially for those of his own house,
he have denied the faith and is worse
than an infidel.
>> Infidel is a nonbeliever.
So therefore, you take care of mama
because she's widow. the main source of
uh providing for the home has passed
away and the children take care of mama
in that order. That's all I got.
>> All right, thank you for that. Hope that
answered their question as we move on to
our next one.
>> Next one. Shula Aul Joby asks, "Should
we keep praying for the same thing until
we receive it or just pray once and have
faith that we will get it?" Philippians
4:E6 is given.
>> All right. Philippians 4 and 6. When it
come to praying, is it once or
what do you do, Jerome?
You can um pray [clears throat] once or
you can pray multiple times. It's it's
it's nothing in the word of God that's
against either way. And and just because
you praying a whole lot though, that
that don't necessarily mean you're going
to get it either. But either way you do
it, it's fine. Okay? But I wanted to
show you a scripture how the Lord did
pray about the same thing more than
once. Okay? So let's go to uh Matthew's
chapter 26
and read verse 36
to 44.
>> Matthew 26.
>> Yeah.
>> And
>> 36 through 4
>> 44. Okay. It says, "Then cometh Jesus
with them unto a place called
Gethsemane, and saith unto the
disciples, sit ye here while I go and
pray yonder."
And he took with him Peter and the two
sons of Zebedee, and began to be
sorrowful and very heavy.
Then saith he unto them, "My soul is
exceedingly sorrowful, even unto death.
Try ye here, and watch with me." And he
went a little further and fell on his
face and prayed, saying, "Oh my father,
if it be possible, let this cup pass
from me. Nevertheless, not as I will,
but as thou wil."
And he cometh unto the disciples, and
findeth them asleep, and saith unto
Peter, What could ye not watch with me
one hour? Watch and pray that ye enter
not into temptation. The spirit indeed
is willing, but the flesh is weak. He
went away again the second time and
prayed, saying, "Oh my father, if this
cup may not pass away from me except I
drink it, thy will be done." And he came
and found them asleep again, for their
eyes were heavy. and he left them and
went away again and prayed the third
time saying the same words.
>> Yeah, that's all I got on
>> Yes, sir.
>> Let's look at a parable that Jesus gave.
Let's go into Luke the 18th chapter and
read 1-6.
Okay,
>> that is Luke 18:es 1-6.
It says, "And he spake a parable unto
them to this end, that man ought always
to pray and not to faint,
saying, There was in a city a judge,
which feared not God, neither regarded
man. And there was a widow in that city,
and she came unto him, saying, "Avenge
me of mine adversary." And he would not
for a while. But afterward he said
within himself, though I fear not God,
nor regard man, yet because this widow
troubleth me, I will avenge her, least
by her continual coming, she weary me."
And the Lord said, "Hear what the unjust
judge saith."
>> Keep reading.
>> Oh. And shall not God avenge his own
elect which cried day and night unto
him, though he bear long with them?
>> You You missed something.
Ver I ended at verse six and it said,
"And the Lord said, hear what the
unjudge unjust judge said." Verse seven,
"And
>> and shall not God avenge his own elect
which cry day and night unto him, though
he bear long with them?"
>> Well, well, well, I must I must have
missed something in there.
>> Uhhuh.
to uh start back and and start back at
uh verse uh uh two and and and read.
>> Okay. Verse two says, "Saying there was
in a city a judge which feared not God,
neither regarded man.
>> And there and there was a widow in that
city, and she came unto him, saying,
Avenge me of my adversary."
And he would not for a while, but
afterward he said within himself,
"Though I fear not God, nor regard man,
yet because this widow troubleth me, I
will avenge her, least by her continual
coming, she weary me."
And the Lord said, "Hear what the unjust
judge saith.
And shall not God avenge his own elect
which cry day and night unto him, though
he bear long with them.
I tell you that he will avenge them
speedily. Nevertheless, when the son of
man cometh, shall he find fi find faith
on the earth.
>> That's enough. But listen what the
unjust said. Jesus gave that parable to
let you know. Just like that uh widow w
that judge down until he did what she
requests. You keep praying. If you have
to pray for the same thing over and
over, you keep doing it. That's what
Jesus is telling you here.
That's all I have to say.
>> Yeah. All right. Thank you for that.
Hope that answered your question as we
continue to move on.
>> Moving on. Mac Muddy Waters asks, "Are
there any verses on knowing if somebody
is the one or if a partner is in God's
will for someone?" Like knowing who is
the one,
>> right? Is there a way of knowing who is
the one? Julius,
>> you pray to God for whatever you ask for
or whatever you want. Be right. you be
right. I don't see any scriptures about
who is the one. That's a personal thing
between you and the Lord. You know, so
the book said, well, the question says,
uh,
if a partner is in God's will for
someone, how do you know? The book say
you will know them by their fruits.
So therefore, but I will counsel you on
this right here. Let's go to second
Corinthians according to the book.
That's the thing between you and the
Lord on knowing who the one is. So many
people said, "Oh, this the one and and
then later on they find out it was the
one."
Sometimes you can miss the one. Uh 2
Corinthians 6, brother James, one verse.
2 Corinthians 6 and read verse 14 for
me. When you get it, brother, go ahead
and read. Take counsel this right here
according to the book. Go ahead. Be ye
not unequally yolked together with
unbelievers.
>> Uhhuh.
>> For what fellowship hath righteousness
with unrighteousness?
>> Uhhuh.
>> And what what communion have light with
darkness?
>> So [clears throat]
you're looking for somebody that's the
one. See if they in the faith, the true
faith of God. Make sure that you're in
the true faith of God. But be ye not
unequally yolked with unbelievers.
cuz you know it you could be starting
out with problems. So you pray about
that. That's all I got to say about
that.
>> Have a meeting in the mind. See what's
in the mind before you move any further.
>> There you go.
>> All right. Thank you for that, brother.
Hope that answered that question as we
move on to our next one.
>> Next one. Brett asks, "Is it possible
that us black people were all over of
all over the world after Noah and his
sons repopulated the earth?"
>> Yes. Caller repopulation.
>> Well, the term us black people is too
nebulous.
M
>> when it come to black people, we are a
minority.
I'm not concerned about us black people
and where we are. What I'm concerned
about is us, the Hebrew Israelite, that
hap just happened to be black. What
happened to us according to what God uh
h put on us and had it prophesied in the
Deuteronomy 28th chapter.
So what does US black people mean? That
means nothing to me. We dealing with
Israel. Our first uh slaver was black
people, Egypt. Then when we left Egypt,
we went to war with the Canaanites.
Then you got the Assyrians, took out the
northern tribe, which is black people.
So black people are too nebulous. I'm
not concerned about that. I'm concerned
about what happened to Israel and uh
black and white people hurt us as a
people.
So it don't make no difference to me
what color is what thus said the Lord
and what and who Israel is. So I'll know
what to expect according to thus said
the Lord. That's all I have to say.
>> All right. I hope that answered your
question there as we move on to our next
one.
>> Next one. The best force asks in first
John 5 verse 18. What is the difference
being born of God and being begotten of
God?
>> The difference between the two, born of
God and begotten of God. Brother Julius,
>> let's let's read the scripture first.
First John 5 and 18.
Okay.
>> And and part of the answer is it depends
upon the context in which it's written
because both both uh begotten and also
uh born of God can have two different
definitions. Go ahead read the
scripture. 1 John 5:18 James.
>> We know that whatsoever is born of God
again.
whosoever
>> who I'm sorry we know that whosoever is
born of God sinnth not
>> but he that is begotten of God keepeth
himself and that wicked one toucheth him
not.
>> Now according to this scripture I see
two different definitions we know that
whosoever is born of God sinnth not. So
as long as you flesh and blood you can
sin.
I don't care how much word of God you
got in it. you flesh and blood and you
can sin. So in that context who's uh
when you are uh born again or when you
are uh got your glorified body you can't
sin. Okay. But he that is begotten of
God keepeth himself. Why do he have to
keep himself? Because he had to always
keep his body in subjection because he
is flesh and blood.
Now the definition of begotten means to
be brought into uh existence by a
parent.
Okay? In that context, in the flesh and
blood context, let me show you. Let's go
to Genesis chapter 5.
And you read the whole chapter on your
own, but we just going to read a couple
of verses to show you that begotten in
this context happens to be being brought
into existence by a parent.
When you get it, read verse three. This
is the first man, Adam. Go ahead and
read it.
>> And Adam lived
130 years and begat a son in his own
likeness after his image and called his
name Seth.
>> So, Adam and Eve had Cain and Abel. But
then it goes right here. It goes right
to uh right to Seth 130 years later.
Okay. But he came forth the parents.
Verse four.
>> And the days of Adam after he had
begotten Seth were 800 years, and he
begat sons and daughters.
>> So that fits the definition of to be
brought into existence by parents. See,
we've heard of Cain and Abel, but we
haven't heard of Seth and the other sons
and daughters that he had. Adam died at
930 years old. Another lesson. Now,
let's go to uh let's go and look at uh
St. John 3
and 16. Let's look at
a divine begotten
St. John 3 and verse 16. Because people
go into Paul's writings and you can go
to other places that Paul writing where
it can say same thing but it could have
different definitions. You have to read
the Bible in proper context. John 3 and
16. Look at this. Be begotten.
This is this is a divine begotten. Go
ahead. For God so loved the world that
he gave his only begotten son that
whosoever believeth in him should not
perish but have everlasting life.
>> So Jesus didn't come by way of what you
call the fleshly uh when a man lay with
a woman that angel put that seed into
Mary. Okay. That's why he's begotten of
the father. But uh I'm looking for the
scripture dre that says we are begotten
by a lively hope concerning us. So now
we on the path of righteousness. We got
the word of God in us. So now that is a
type of beginner.
We are begotten by a lively hope. I
wrote it down and I misplaced the
>> first Peter. First Peter uh one and
three.
>> Let's go there. First Peter. Thank you
brother. First Peter 1.
First Peter first chapter and verse and
verse three
>> it says blessed be the God and father of
our Lord Jesus Christ which according to
his abundant mercy have begotten us
again unto a lively hope by the
resurrection of Jesus Christ from the
dead.
>> So in this context here notice he said
begotten again. You was already brought
forth by parents, but now you in the
word of God. Now you in the spirit. Now
that is a another kind of beginner
through the spirit through the word of
God. But we waiting on our glorified
bodies. That's what we waiting on for
the resurrection or either for the
change in the body. So the there's
differences in definition depending upon
context. Anybody else?
>> Yeah. Just one thing I'd like to say
concerning the father. He said, "God, my
son,
>> yes.
>> This day have I begotten thee."
>> Yes, sir.
>> And there was a day when he went from
flesh when he wrote rose as a as an
immortal. It said in the second chapter
of Psalm and also it it says in Acts, I
think where it spoke speaks of the
resurrection and quotes that.
>> Yes.
>> Same thing.
>> [snorts]
>> That's why he said thou this day my uh
this day have I begotten thee. He went
from that flesh from to that spirit.
>> Uhhuh. See, so what day did he become
the son of God? Romans the first
chapter. Start reading
>> Romans 1.
It says
>> that verse one
>> it says Paul a servant of Jesus Christ
called to be an apostle separated unto
the gospel of God which he had promised
of four by his prophets in the holy
scriptures concerning his son Jesus
Christ our Lord which was made of the
seed of David according to the flesh and
declared to be the son of God with power
according to the spirit of holiness by
the resurrection from the dead.
>> Yes sir.
>> Now that was the day that he begot him
from man in the god family. See so
sometime you get begotten and born
again. It can be the same thing
but then sometime it can be simply
because if you had gone into a it would
have put I I don't I forgot where it is
now in Acts.
>> Acts 13.
>> Acts 13. Go and read it.
>> Acts 13 and what
>> and 33.
>> Okay. Acts 13 and 30
33 says, "God hath fulfilled the same
unto us their children, in that he hath
raised up Jesus again, as it is also
written in the second psalm, thou art my
son, this day have I begotten thee."
>> Yes, sir.
>> So, that's when he he became the son of
God. What day? The day that he rose from
the dead. But then like Julia said, you
can be begotten to a lively hope. But
this here, this day I begotten thee,
that's when he was born again. Like it
says he was born not of the flesh and
not of the will of man, but of God.
>> Yes.
>> What day was that? When he was begotten.
That's why when you go in the Romans the
8th chapter, it tell you he is the first
born of many brethren. First born of
what? the first that was born again. So
in that case you have begotten and born
is the same and other cases you have
begotten and born mean two different
things.
That's all I have to say.
>> All right. Thank you for that. Hope that
answered your question as we move on to
our next one with a time check.
>> The time is 8:00. Next question. Dborah
Wilder asked for you to explain Matthew
6 22 and 23.
>> All right. Matthew 6:22 and 23 dealing
with light and darkness, your works,
your walk. Let's go and read that,
brother.
Matthew 6 and pick it up at the verse
22.
>> Okay. It says, "The light of the body is
the eye. If therefore thine eye be
single, thy whole body shall be full of
light.
>> So if thy eye be single, if it's toward
God and you doing what he say, then your
body shall be full of light. 23
>> But if thine eye be evil, thy whole body
shall be full of darkness.
If therefore the light that is in thee
be darkness, how great is that darkness?
>> Yes. So, and if I be evil, then our
whole body shall be full of darkness,
and nothing worse than knowing what
right is and doing wrong. Read 24.
>> No man can serve two masters. For either
he will hate the one and love the other,
or else he will hold on to the one and
despise the other.
>> Ye cannot serve Oh, I'm sorry.
>> Go ahead. Ye cannot serve God and
mammon.
>> Yep. So if you walking with God and
doing all these say, hey, your body is
full of light. But if not, hey, it's
full of darkness. But let's go over to
Luke 11 right quick. Luke 11 and pick it
up at verse 34. Luke 11 and 34.
>> Okay. It says, "The light of the body is
the eye. Therefore, when thine eye is
single, thy whole body also is full of
light.
>> Mhm.
>> But when thine eye is evil, thy body
also is full of darkness.
>> Yeah. You following God, hey, you full
of light. You following Satan or Rome,
hey, then you full of darkness. Go
ahead.
>> Take heed therefore that the light which
is in thee be not darkness.
>> Right. One more verse. If thy whole body
therefore be full of light, having no
part of dark or no part dark, the whole
shall be full of light, as when the
bright shining of a candle doeth give
thee light.
>> Yes. Because when you walking with God
and you got that light shining, hey,
then you glorifying your father which
siteth in heaven. So, hey, praise God
for that. But that's all I got. Anybody
else?
All right. We hope that answered your
question. We're gonna move on to our
next one.
>> Next one. Linda Beach asks, "If a person
keeps a locket on them with their
daughter's ashes in them, does that make
them unclean?"
>> Yes, it does. All day, every day.
Because those ashes are part of a body
that was that was cremated.
and um putting ashes of the dead in
jewelry that came from the ancient
memorial practices and became popular in
the mid 1800s.
Um jewelry and cremation u people use
that use hair and use bone and blood to
keep their loved ones close at hand. But
let's go into Genesis 2 and 7 and see
what the Lord said because yeah, you
unclean all the time with those ashes
around your neck.
And let's see what the Lord said.
Genesis 2 and 7. Go ahead, brother.
>> And the Lord God formed man of the dust
of the ground and breathed into his
nostrils the breath of life and man
became a living soul.
>> So Lord got man from the dust of the
ground. One more verse. Genesis 3 and
19. After man had sinned, what did the
Lord say to him in that verse 19?
>> In the sweat of thy face shalt thou eat
bread, till thou return unto the ground.
For out of it was thou taken, for dust
thou art, and unto dust shalt thou
return.
>> So you're supposed to return everything
that's a part of the body to the ground.
If you want to obey what does this 19
say that you're supposed to Hey, for
dust thou art and unto dust shall thou
return. So yeah, having that locket
around your neck makes you unclean all
the time. And if you would like to turn
the page and newness of life and not be
unclean all the time, you must dispose
of that locket. And there are some nice
ways that you can do it. But you unclean
all the time and that's all I got.
All right, we're going to move on to our
next question.
>> Moving on. Elizabeth Cochrell says,
"According to the Bible, God did not
hold anyone 19 and under accountable for
their bad behavior." How should
disrespect and disobedience be handled
at age 19 without getting physical
according to the Bible?
>> All right. So according to the Bible,
Dre, um, shed some light, brother.
>> Yeah. So let's let's go over to Numbers
14. Numbers 14 and we going to pick it
up at verse 29 because Israel
went into the wilderness
and they sinned while they were in the
wilderness and this is what happened.
Read verse 29 to 31, brother. Go ahead.
>> Okay. TW numbers uh 14:29 says, "Your
carcasses shall fall in this wilderness,
and all that were numbered of you
according to your whole number, from 20
years old and upward, which have
murmured against me.
Doubtless ye shall not come into the
land concerning which I swear to make
you dwell therein, save Caleb the son of
Jaffa, and Joshua the son of Nun.
But your little ones which ye said
should be a prey, them will I bring in,
and they shall know the land which ye
have despised. So those that were
uh 20 years old and upward did not make
it into the promised land of that
generation besides Joshua and Caleb. And
those that were younger came in.
But let's look at another incident.
Let's go to second Kings the 2 chapter
and we gonna read verses 22 to 24.
>> Read read that when you get there,
brother.
>> Okay. You said 2 Kings
>> 2 Kings 2.
>> Okay.
>> 22- 24.
>> Okay. It says, "And he went forth unto
the spring of the waters, and cast the
salt in there, and said, thus sayeth the
Lord, I have healed these waters. There
shall not be from thence any more death
or barren land."
>> What verse is that?
>> That was 21.
>> Okay, go ahead.
>> So the waters were healed unto this day,
according to the saying of Alicia, which
he spake.
>> Mhm. And he and he went up from then
unto Bethl. And as he was going up by
the way, there came forth little
children out of the city, and mocked
him, and said unto him, "Go up, thou
bald head. Go up, thou bald head."
>> So these children was mocking Elisha,
saying, "Go up, thou bowhead. Go ahead."
and he turned back and looked on them
and cursed them in the name of the Lord
and there came forth two she bears out
of the wood and tear 40 into children of
them.
>> So because they was mocking Elisha,
those children got dealt with and 42
of them got torn by she bears. Now let's
what do you do? You ask the question,
well, what do you do with a 19-year-old?
Let's go to Proverbs 22 and6.
Proverbs 22 and6.
Read that when you get there, brother.
>> It says, "Train up a child in the way he
should go, and when he is old, he will
not depart from it."
>> So that's what we do. We train them up
when they're young, and when they get
older, they won't depart from it. But
there's another situation that takes
place if you have a stubborn child. It's
the last place. Let's go to Deuteronomy
21 and read verses 18 to 21.
Deuteronomy 21 18- 21.
You can't do that now, but this is what
the Lord said in the order. Go ahead. 18
21 18- 21. Go ahead. 21:18-21
says, "If a man have a stubborn and
rebellious son, which will not obey the
voice of his father, or the voice of his
mother, and that when they have chasti
chastened him, he will not hearken unto
them. Then shall his father and his
mother lay hold on him, and bring him
out unto the elders of the city of his
city, and unto the gate of his place.
And they shall say unto the elders of
his city, this our son is stubborn and
rebellious. He will not obey our voice.
He is a glutton and a drunkard.
And all the men of his city shall stone
him with stones that he die. So shalt
thou put evil of what? Evil away from
among you, and all Israel shall hear and
fear. Problem is it ain't much fear now.
In fact,
>> children are oppressors right now. But
that's prophecy. That's what the book
said would happen because we are in
rebellion against our God. That's all I
got.
>> Yeah, that's right, brother Dre. And and
also it's good for that that child is
being disrespectful for the parent to
remind them of that Exodus 20 and 12
where it say, "Honor thy father and thy
mother." that thy days may be long upon
the land which the Lord thy God giveth
thee.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Thank you for that explanation, brother.
As we continue to move on,
>> moving on. Shality says
Jesus said he came to do the father's
will. Where in scripture can it be read
what exactly the father's will is?
>> All right, guest caller. What exactly is
the will of the father?
>> Well, in order to look, the scripture
for the will of the father is from
Genesis to Revelation.
>> That's right.
>> But to give but to give you uh uh if you
read from Genesis to Revelation, you'll
know what his will is. But to give you
brief description, we got to find out
what happened to man in the first place.
Let's go into Psalms the 82nd chapter of
Psalm read verses 1 and 2
then 6 and 7.
>> Okay.
Psalm 82:es 1 and two says, "God
standeth in the congregation of the
mighty. He judgeth among the gods."
How long
>> now?
This is talking about man. But God is
telling you what your potential is.
>> Stand in the congregation of the mighty
and he judges among the gods. Remember
now, Abel one, Abel two in the Godhead,
that's the father and the son. So this
talking about man, but go ahead and what
did he say?
>> How long will ye judge unjustly and
accept the persons of the wicked?
>> And that's what they did. They accepted
the person of Satan in the Garden of
Eden instead of God. Skip down to verse
six and continue.
I have said ye are gods and all of you
are children of the most high
but ye shall die like men and fall like
one of the princes.
>> So now man is dying. Man was not
supposed to die,
>> right?
>> God created man to live forever. But
what happened is man did something and
God brought in death. He said because
you know he said so because you accept
the person of the wicked. He said look I
said you are I I've said you are
gods
and you all the children of the most
high but you going to die like men. So
now what is Jesus main purpose? What did
God send Jesus to do?
That is a reverse what man caused God to
do in the garden of Eden. And let's go
into St. John the 6th chapter and we're
going to read from 38 to 40.
>> Verse 38 to 40.
>> We can read a lot of other but I'm just
giving you a brief description of what
God what the father will is. This is
what Jesus came to do his will. Read it.
For I came down from heaven, not to do
mine own will, but the will of him that
sent me.
>> And
this is the Father's will which has sent
me, that of all which he hath given me,
I should lose nothing, but should raise
it up again at the last day.
>> Now that's Now look at this.
God didn't man wasn't supposed to die
but man messed up and he end up dying.
So Jesus was sent to reverse that
because that is the father's will. Read
the next verse.
>> And this is the will of him that sent me
that everyone which seeth the son and
believeth on him may have everlasting
life and I will raise him up at the last
day.
He keeps saying the same thing, raising
him up at the last day.
Read verse 44.
No man can come to me except the father
which has sent me. Draw him and I will
raise him up at the last day.
>> Read verse 54.
Whosoever eateth my flesh and drinkkeeth
my blood have eternal life, and I will
raise him up at the last day.
>> So that is the father's will
to raise this man up so he can become
God like he intended him to do before he
messed up in the Garden of Eden. That's
all they got to say.
>> All right, thank you for that. I hope
that answered your question as we move
on.
>> Moving on. Uh Melon Proud asks, "What is
the best way to go about sharing the
word of God with people?"
>> All right. So, what is the best way to
go about by about sharing this true
sweet word of God with people? Brother
Julius,
>> first of all, you you you uh the way I
do it is the best I can according to the
scriptures, which is to ask people uh do
they believe in God? Do they believe in
his word. The key part is to listen to
their uh listen to their answers and I
mean listen carefully and then make them
uh read to prove their answers. make
them read, give book, chapter, and verse
and uh give scripture. But here's a as a
servant of God, this is what how we
should reach all people. Let's go to
Galatians chapter 6.
One of the ways that I find uh that work
very well.
You'd be surprised your tone uh your
approach. You'd be surprised people will
listen to you when you have something to
say. And the way I do it, I make people
challenge what they have traditionally
been taught. And I do it in the spirit
of meekness according to the scriptures
the best that I can. Galatians 6,
brother James, and read verse six.
>> Let him that is taught in the word
communicate unto him that teacheth in
all good things. So you are taught in
the word of God. You you are seasoned.
And so you have to have a seasoned
approach. Second Timothy, my last place.
Second Timothy the 2 chapter. Second
Timothy chapter 2.
And when you get it, Brother James,
we're going to read 24. We're going to
read verse 24
and verse 26.
>> Okay.
Second Timothy the 2 chapter verse 24.
What the book say?
>> It says, "And the servant of the Lord
must not strive
>> but be gentle unto all men."
>> See, that's that the approach. You can't
come at people harsh. You can't come
like you know it all. You have to give
people room like we didn't know at one
time. Go ahead, brother.
>> Apt to teach patient.
Verse 26. You want me to keep
>> 25 25
>> in meekness instructing those that
oppose themselves.
>> Yes.
>> If if God preventure will give them
repentance to the acknowledging of the
truth.
>> One more.
>> And that and that they may recover
themselves out of the snare of the devil
who are taken captive by him at his
will. So when you are true servant of
God, your intention should always be to
draw like the Lord got it written, I
have drawn you with loving kindness. So
we have to s have the same approach as
our god sisters and brothers and we have
to be uh uh uh in meekness which is
humility not thinking that we know
everything but read to the people and
say give me book chapter verse prove
your prove that ministry to me and it
works every in most cases it works if
they really want to hear and there's
nothing like hearing I'm going to go
home and I'm going to check out what you
just told me it's a beautiful thing
that's the best that I can do. Anybody
else?
>> All right, let your light shine. Okay,
we're going to move on to our next
question with a time.
>> Next.
>> Yes, the time is 8:20. Cassie Lee asks,
"Is there an IOG reference book list
available so that I can order these
books to read or reference? I purchased
the Zanderan dictionary in the last two
million years.
>> All right, those are some good books to
purchase. And there's some other books
if you go to the website and go into the
word store and it'll let you know about
some of the other books like the four
winds of heaven.
>> That book right there will let you know
for sure uh about world history and the
end times. will walk you all the way
down if you want to learn of that. Then
we have the dietary law about the beasts
that you shall eat and the beast you
shall not eat and the other things that
you can eat and other things that you
cannot eat. And we have a feast overview
which is Leviticus the 23rd chapter
about the Lord's feast days upon which
we keep anyway. And brother Julius you
just held up a book and what book is
that you held up? That was the atlas of
the Bible. We also have a pictorial
history of the Italian people and
another book that's written by the
Israel of God that you must get and that
is called the four winds of heaven. You
can find all these resources on just go
to IOG website and it'll it'll guide
you. Uh once you get there, check the uh
take a picture of the QR code. it'll
direct you to all of uh the books that
we have and we so those are some
wonderful wonderful resources. Another
book that we have is the Zundance Bible
compact Bible dictionary. You want to
you want to have all the tools that you
need, get you some encyclopedias. You
can order those online and very very
helpful and it's backed by history.
>> Yep. So, that's just some of the books
that we um can point you in the
direction of. But like Julia say that
four winds of heaven, hey, it to let you
know what's going on over there in the
east and all that good stuff. And hey,
be prepared to gain all this good
knowledge. All right, we're going to
move on to our next question.
>> Next question. Ricky Oine asks, "Is it
okay to shave your head and your face on
a Saturday?"
Shimone, can you shave your head and
your face on the Sabbath day?
>> Um, I recommend you do your shaving of
your head before the Sabbath day. You
got
>> you got six days out of the week take
care of your shaving of your head. And
uh in regard beard, you know, hopefully
you don't have to shave all your beard
off, but if you happen to be in a
situation where you have to shave your
beard, try to do that before the Sabbath
day as well. You know, before sundown,
before before the Sabbath day start, you
know, there's verses I can take you to,
but that that's all I got to say.
Anybody else want to add?
>> Yeah, because that that Isaiah 58 tell
us that that day is a holy day unto the
Lord. That's right.
So you do no more than you have to
on that day. All right,
we're going to move on to our next
question.
>> Next one. P. Smith asks in Psalms 81 3
and 4. Should we be blowing a trumpet
which is listed as the chauffear in
Strong's concordians definition?
Is there scripture that you know of that
indicates this is no longer to be done?
>> All right. And that's Psalms 81 and 3-4.
Brother Julius, they're asking about
should we be blowing trumpets.
>> When you get it, James Psalms
813 or 4. When you get it, my brother,
go ahead and read it. blow up the
trumpet in the new moon in the time
appointed on our solemn feast day.
>> For this was a statue for Israel and a
law of the God of Jacob.
>> Yes, sir. Trumpets announce things.
Announces war. It announces uh retreat.
It It announces uh uh it announces feast
days. It also announces the coming of
the Lord. But all of that was done under
the Levitical priesthood.
There is no Levitical priesthood today.
We are all up under the blood of Jesus.
But let me show you in the Old Testament
uh where it was done. We just read Psalm
81 and that's what they did. But now
let's go to Joshua the 6th chapter.
This is just one of the places in the
Old Testament. Joshua the 6th chapter,
brother James. And what we going to do?
We're going to read verses 12 and 13.
This is when uh Israel uh came down to
Jericho in the days of uh when the walls
of Jericho fell flat.
Go ahead.
>> And Joshua rose early in the morning and
the priests took up the ark of the Lord.
and seven priests bearing seven trumpets
of ram's horns before the ark of the
Lord went on continually and blew with
the trumpets and the armed men went
before them. But the reward, the reward
came after the ark of the Lord, the
priest going on and blowing with the
trumpets.
>> So now in the Old Testament, who blew
the trumpets?
>> The priest.
>> Priests. Another example, first Kings
the first chapter. I got one place after
this one. First Kings chapter 1. First
Kings 1. And what we going to do,
brother James, we going to read verses
32 and 34. First Kings 1 32 and 34. When
you get it, brother, go ahead and read.
>> First, we got to have two witnesses. Go
ahead. And King David said, "Call me
Zadok the priest." And Nathan the
prophet and Banayiah the son of Joha.
And they came before the king.
>> Now skip down to verse 34.
>> And let Zadok the priest and Nathan the
prophet anoint him there king over
Israel, and blow ye with the trumpet,
and say, "God save."
that was under the old covenant and
Jesus had not came on the scene yet. But
now
now Jesus came on the scene and now
Jesus done shed his blood. That's why
the veil of the temple was in twain
because you're no longer under the
Levitical priesthood. Now you're under
the Jesus or Mechisedc priesthood. So
now let's look who blow the trumpets and
who will blow the trumpets. Uh, let's go
to Revelation the 8th chapter. Last book
of the Bible. Revelation the 8th
chapter. You don't need to blow the show
for it no more. There is no Levitical
priesthood.
Revelation chapter 8. We're going to
read vers two.
Verse two. Revelation 8 and two. And
then we're going to skip to six. James.
>> Okay.
>> Go ahead, brother. And I saw the seven
angels which stood before God, and to
them were given seven trumpets.
>> So now you got seven angels. Why not the
priests? Because we're under the blood
of Jesus. Now go ahead, brother.
>> Verse six.
>> And the seven angels which had the seven
trumpets prepared themselves to sound.
So now you can read all the whole
chapter but just Revelation 9 and1 and
then we're done.
>> And the fifth angel sounded and I saw a
star fall from heaven unto the earth and
to him was given the key of the
bottomless pit.
>> And it goes trumpet number six. And then
the seventh trumpet announces the coming
of the Lord, the resurrection of the
dead. Because trumpets mean something.
But notice it is not the priests. It is
the angels who are blowing the seven
angels that's blowing the trumpets. You
don't need to show for you don't need to
blow no trumpets. Just need to keep his
commandments. That's all I got, brother
Cornell.
>> Yes, sir. Good wisdom there, brother.
And hope they received it as we continue
to move on to our next question.
>> Moving on. uh philosophy asks in 1
Corinians 6 verse 19 it talks about the
Holy Spirit or Holy Ghost in the KJV
being inside us. I'm confused because I
know all you all teaching show how the
Holy Spirit ghost isn't actually in us,
but verses like these make it confusing.
How would I tell someone the common
belief of Holy Spirit is false?
>> All right. Well, let's go to 1
Corinthians 6 and 19.
And when you get there, brother, go
ahead and read it and the guest caller
will help this question by removing the
confusion. Go ahead, brother.
>> Okay. It says, "What know ye not that
your body is the temple of the Holy
Ghost, which is in you, which ye have of
God, and ye are not your own?"
No.
The question that they ask
is how would I tell someone that the
common belief you know uh belief of the
Holy Spirit is false?
Well, my answer to you is you can't
unless you know what context is used in.
M
>> now I want you I want you uh uh uh uh
read that 19th verse again and pay
attention so we going to see what what
what this Holy Spirit where it where it
is. Read it again.
>> It says what know ye not that your body
is the temple of the Holy Ghost which is
in you?
So I let you know that finish this.
That's the end of the verse.
>> No, no. Which ye have of God and ye are
not your own.
>> Okay. So this particular Holy Ghost uh
spirit you have to put it in context. We
have a series that's called the spirit
of God in its many forms.
>> Yeah.
>> So you have to know what context is in.
So this particular spirit that's that uh
that your body is a temple for
is the word of God. Now let's go and
have a real good look at it. Okay.
Now let's go and look at the uh uh uh uh
Isaiah the 9th chapter
and we're going to read verse 6 and 7.
Okay. Isaiah 9
6 and 7 says, "For unto us a child is
born. Unto us a son is given."
>> No, I'm I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
>> With the wrong
>> We got to back up. I mean, uh uh I want
you to read
Ezekiel.
>> Okay. chapter and we're going to read
verse three and skip down and read verse
8 and 10 because the Lord had broke is
breaking this down simple because he
knew that people going to be confused
about this. Ezekiel 2:es
3 [clears throat]
and then skip down and read 8 and 10.
>> Okay. Ezekiel 2:3 says, "And he said
unto me, son of man, I send thee to the
children of Israel, to a rebellious
nation that have rebelled against me.
They and their fathers have transgressed
against me even unto this day."
>> Let's skip down to verse eight and
continue to 10.
>> But thou, son of man, hear what I say
unto thee. Be not thou rebellious like
the rebellious house. Open thy mouth and
eat that I give thee.
>> And when I And when I looked, behold, a
hand was sent unto me, and lo, a roll of
a book was therein,
and he spread it before me, and it was
written within and without, and there
was written therein lamentations, and
mourning and woe.
Now, he's a son of man. I want you to
eat that which I give you. But what was
in it? He he he sent a a roll, didn't
it? With writing in it.
>> Yes.
>> Written in and out. So, now let's see
what he did. Did you finish that?
>> Yes, I did, sir.
>> Go right on into the third chapter of
Ezekiel and we're going to read verse 1
through 4.
>> Okay. It says, "Moreover, he said unto
me, son of man, eat that thou findest,
eat this roll, and go speak unto the
house of Israel. So I opened my mouth,
and he caused me to eat that roll." And
he said unto me, "Son of man, cause thy
belly to eat, and fill thy boughs with
this roll that I give thee." Then did I
eat it, and it was in my mouth as honey
or for sweetness. And he said unto me,
son of man, go
get thee unto the house of Israel, and
speak with my words unto them.
Now he said, a hand with a roll in it,
you know, like a scroll written written
on both sides. And he told Ezekiel to
eat it. Now once he ate the ate the
roll, then he said, "Now go speak my
words." What's he talking about? How do
you eat a a roll? How do you eat a uh a
documentation with writing on it? By
read
>> read it.
>> Now I give you another example. Let's go
into Revelation
the 10th chapter.
We're going to read one and two and skip
down
and read from 8 to 11. Let's do one and
two first. Let me know when you end the
verse.
>> Okay. Uh
Ezekiel I mean I'm sorry. Revelation 10
and1 says, "And I saw another mighty
angel come down from heaven clothed with
a cloud and a rainbow was upon his head,
and his face was as it were the sun, and
his feet as a pillar of fire."
and and for and I'm sorry and he had in
his hand a little book open and he set
his right foot upon the sea and his left
foot upon the earth. That was the end of
verse two.
>> Now, now this angel showed up. He had a
book in his hand, didn't he?
>> Yes, he did.
>> Let's see what he going to do with this
book. Skip now to verse eight and we're
going to read to 11. Go ahead.
And the voice which I heard from heaven
spake unto me again and said, "Go and
take the little book which is open in
the hand of the angel which standeth
upon the sea and upon the earth." And I
went unto the angel and said unto him,
Give me the little book. And he said
unto me, take it and eat it up, and it
shall make thy belly bitter, but it
shall be in thy mouth sweet as honey.
Now, how do you eat a book?
>> Read.
>> There you go. You read.
>> And I took the little book out of the
angel's hand and ate it up, and it was
in my mouth sweet as honey. And as soon
as I had eaten it, my belly was bitter.
>> Go ahead. and and he said unto me, "Thou
must prophesy again before many peoples
and the and nations and tongues and
kings."
Now look, he didn't tell him it until he
had eaten the book.
>> In other words, he read the book and he
knew what was in it. And now he said he
uses mouth and belly is because the Lord
know that this man is so dumb until he
had to make it real simple for him. Like
he ate the roll now you ate the book.
Well for when you got through eating
then you uh uh you go speak his word.
But we want to make it real clear.
Let's go into Jeremiah the 15th chapter.
Read verses 15 and 16.
Jeremiah 15
says, "Oh Lord, thou knowest. Remember
me and visit me and revenge me of my
persecutors. Take me not away and thy
longsuffering. Know that for thy sake I
have suffered rebuke.
Thy words were found, and I did eat
them. And thy word was unto me the joy
and rejoicing of my heart. For I am
called by thy name, O Lord God of hosts.
>> He said, "Now your words were found and
I did eat them." How do you eat the
words of God?
>> Read it.
>> There you go.
Now, let's go and show you what this
word is. Let's go into St. John the 6th
chapter
read 51- 54
verse
51 to 51- 54 sir.
>> Uh-huh.
>> It says again that's St. John 6 and 51
says I am the living bread which came
down from heaven. If any man eat of this
bread, he shall live forever, and the
bread that I will give is my flesh,
which I will give for the life of the
world.
The Jews stro therefore strove among
themselves, saying, How can this man
give us his flesh to eat? Then Jesus
said unto them, "Verily, verily, I say
unto you, except ye eat the flesh of the
Son of Man, and drink his blood, ye have
no life in you.
Whosoever eateth my flesh and drinkkeeth
my blood hath eternal life, and I will
raise him up at the last day."
>> What verse is that?
>> That was verse 54.
He talking about eating his flesh and
drinking his blood. Skip down to 60.
Read 60 and 61.
Many therefore of his disciples when
they had heard this said, "This is a
hard saying. Who can hear it?" When
Jesus knew in himself that his disciples
murmured at it, he said unto them,
"Doeth this offend you?"
>> Uh-huh. Now skip down and read verse 63
and look what he said.
>> It is the spirit that quickenth.
The flesh profitth nothing. The words
that I speak unto you, they are spirit
and they are life.
>> So now once you read this book,
read the book of being taught the word
that's in the book. That word is in you.
And he telling you right here, the word
that he's speaking is spirit. Therefore,
the spirit is in you, which makes you a
temple of the Holy Ghost because his
word is spirit and it is life.
Now, let's go to one last place. Let's
go into Colossians 3. We're going to
read verses 9 and 10. And we're going to
skip down and read verse 16.
Okay. Colossians
3. Oh, I'm sorry. Nine.
>> 9 and 10.
>> Colossians 3.
>> Mhm.
>> Third chapter verses 9 and 10. And you
skip down to verse 16.
>> Okay. It says, "Lie not one to another,
seeing that ye have put off the old man
with his deeds, and have put on the new
man, which is renewed in knowledge after
the image of him that created him."
>> Now, in a new man, you renewed in
knowledge.
After the image of him that created him.
Go ahead.
>> That was verse 10. And then you said,
"Go to 16." Correct.
Mhm.
>> Let the word of Christ dwell in you
richly in all wisdom, teaching and
admonishing one another in psalms and
hymns and spiritual songs, singing with
grace in your hearts to the Lord.
So that spirit of God that's in you,
that is the word of God.
And when the word of God is in you, then
you are a temple.
You are a a temple of the Holy Ghost.
So the word that goes in the thing to
the spirit that goes inside of you is
the word of God. So what you do is you
take them. This is just a few scriptures
out of many that show you that.
That's why the Lord said I stand at the
door and knock. If you open up, that's
talking about the door of your mind. I
will come in and suck with you and you
with me. God ain't going to walk inside
of your head, but he going to come by
way of his word.
Do not
what you need to do is get that serious
so when somebody ask you a question, you
be able to answer because the spirit of
God come in many forms. But the one that
we're talking about here
in uh uh uh 1 Corinthians 6:19 is
talking about the word of God
because you're a temple of his word
which is spirit. That's all I have to
say.
>> All right. Thank you for that and we
hope that that helped to remove some of
that confusion as we move on to our next
question.
>> Uh yes. Philosophy also says, "I was
told that Isaiah 9 verse 6 and Isaiah 48
verse 16 shows the Trinity.
How God and Jesus and the Holy Spirit is
three persons but one being. I'm
confused how the Holy Spirit is just an
angel because these verses make sense.
All right, brother James,
>> go right ahead.
Oh, brother James
696.
Isaiah
>> Isaiah 9:6 says, "For unto us a child is
born, and unto us a son is given, and
the government shall be upon his
shoulder, and his name shall be called
Wonderful, Counselor, the Mighty God,
the Everlasting Father, the Prince of
Peace."
>> Now, where is it that you see a Trinity
in there?
got nothing to do with the trinity.
That's talking about Jesus. Read read a
little more
>> of the increase of his government and
peace there shall be no end. Upon the
throne of David and upon his kingdom to
order it and to establish it with
judgment and with justice from
henceforth,
even forever the zeal of the Lord of
hosts will perform this. No, this time
but this child that's going to be born
is Jesus and he going to sit on the
throne of David
and his kingdom going to be forever.
Let's go and show you what I'm talking
about. Let's go into Luke
first chapter.
And when the book say he's a father,
everlasting father, he's a father to us.
>> Yeah. a father to us, but not the uh uh
uh but he ain't the father. But we
talking about the child that was born.
The father ain't never been born.
>> So let's see who it was that was born.
Luke 1 and 26. 26 and 27. Then we and
27. Then we're going to skip down.
>> Okay. Luke 1:26 says, "In the sixth
month, the angel Gabriel was sent from
God unto a city of Galilee named Nazare
Nazareth to a virgin espouseed to a man
whose name was Joseph of the house of
David. And the virgin's name was Mary."
>> Uhhuh.
>> And the angel came in. Okay. Mhm. Skip
down.
>> Verse 30. Verse 30, then continue.
And the angel said unto her, "Fear not,
Mary, for thou has found favor with God.
And behold, thou shalt conceive in thy
womb, and shall bring forth a son, and
shalt call his name Jesus."
>> Uhhuh.
>> He shall be great, and shall be called
the son of the highest. And the Lord God
shall give unto him the throne of his
father David.
Now that's the child unto us a child
child is born and the son is given as
Jesus
>> and you going to call his name Jesus.
And the Lord God is going to give him
the throne of his father David. Go
ahead.
>> And he shall reign over the house of
Jacob forever. And of his kingdom there
shall be no end.
Then
>> now it's talking about Jesus and Jesus
alone in Isaiah.
What verse was that? Did you stop at
verse 3?
>> Yes, sir.
>> And that's it. That's what Isaiah uh uh
uh 9 and and uh uh uh six is talking
about. The child that's born, Jesus.
>> Yeah.
>> And those are his title. And those are
his titles.
That's what it is. Now listen. So now
they ain't got nothing to do with
trinity there. You got one person there
because he said when he said everlasting
father, he's not talking about the
father. It's our father. Cuz it was
Jesus that told Pharaoh in the uh uh in
in the fourth chapter of Exodus that
Israel is my son, my freshborn.
>> Yes. because he adopted Jacob and gave
him his name.
>> So now that's got nothing to do with the
Trinity. That's all about Jesus.
>> Now let's look at the other one. What
was that?
>> Uh was
>> Isaiah 48 verse 16.
>> Okay, read it.
>> It says, "Come ye near unto me. Hear ye
this. I have not spoken in secret from
the beginning. From the time that it
was, there am I. And now the Lord God
and his spirit have sent me.
>> Now, let's back up and see who's doing
this talking here in the first place.
Let's back up and read verse 12 and 13.
>> Okay, first
>> it says, "Hearken unto me, oh Jacob and
Israel, my called. I am he. I am the
first. I am also the last. I also am the
last. My hand hath laid the foundation
of the earth, and my right hand has
spanned the heavens. When I called unto
them, they stand up together.
>> Now, this ain't no angel talking.
That's Jesus talking. And the same
person. Now, you read verse 16.
So since we know who is the one that
that made the foundation of the earth
and who want and the one that spanned
the heaven that was Jesus. Go ahead now.
Now now read 16. Go ahead. Come ye near
unto me. Hear ye this. I have not spoken
in secret from the beginning. From the
time that it was there am I. And now the
Lord God and his spirit has sent me. is
the Lord God of his spirit is talking
and his word because we had read that
the word that the Lord's word uh uh his
words of spirit life in other words he
was uh a Lord God and his spirit sent
him
but now let's go into Luke the 4th
chapter and see who this talking about
Luke 4 and read verses 14-
>> Luke 4-
21 say, "And Jesus returned in the power
of the spirit into Galilee, and there
went out of fame of him through all the
region round about.
And he taught in their synagogues, being
glorified of all. And he came to
Nazareth, where he had been brought up,
and as his custom was, he went into the
synagogue on the Sabbath day, and stood
up for to read."
And there and there was delivered unto
him, the book of the prophet Isaiah. And
when he had opened the book, he found
the place where it was written, "The
spirit of the Lord is upon me, because
he hath anointed me to preach the gospel
to the poor. He had sent me to heal the
brokenhearted, to preach deliverance to
the captives, and recovering of the
sight to the blind, to set at liberty
them that are bruised. to preach the
acceptable year of the Lord. And he
closed the book, and he gave it again to
the minister, and sat down. And the eyes
of all them that were in the synagogue
were fastened on him. And he began to
say unto them, "This day is the
scripture fulfilled in your ears."
So that was Jesus.
The God with his word sent him. That's
why I said, "The spirit of the Lord is
upon me. his word.
So he came and he was sent to heal the
brokenhearted, you know, to loose the
prison, preach the acceptable day of the
Lord. But
he didn't fulfill everything that was
written. Why? Is because he had to die
first. So he was sent by the father.
But as far as the spinity is concerned,
there's nowhere there in that where the
trinity is. The angels don't send
nobody.
The angels are sent.
>> Mhm.
>> St. John 5 and 37 real quick. I want you
to I want you to understand that that uh
who sent who. John 5 and37
>> it says, "And the father himself which
had sent me borne witness of me." The
father himself which hath sent me
have borne witness of me.
>> Ye have said
>> you know he didn't say nothing but no
Holy Ghost right?
>> No.
>> Of his spirit. He said the father
himself which has sent me. finish that
verse.
>> Have borne witness of me. Ye have
neither heard his voice at any time nor
seen his shape.
>> Now that's Jesus. He was the one that
sent. He was the one that came because
and he's the one also that laid the
foundation of the earth and everything
else. So now the father sent Jesus.
But the angels don't send nobody. They
are sent. Let me show you what I'm
talking about.
Let's go into uh uh uh
St. John the 16th chapter.
We're going to read five and six uh uh
5-7 first.
Okay.
St. John 16 5 says, "But now I go my way
to him that sent me, and none of you
askth me."
Did you notice Jesus is always saying to
him that sent me? He didn't said them,
did he?
>> No.
>> Nope.
>> I go my way to him that sent me.
Continue.
>> And none of you askth me whether goest
thou.
But because I have said these things
unto you, sorrow hath filled your heart.
Nevertheless, I tell you the truth. It
is expedient for you that I go away. For
if I go not away, the comforter will not
come unto you, but if I depart, I will
send him unto you. What verse is that?
>> That was verse seven.
>> Okay. He said, I go my way cuz if I
don't go, the comfort won't go won't
come to you. But what he said? But if he
go, he going to do what?
Read that again.
>> Nevertheless, I tell you the truth. It
is expedient for you that I go away. For
if I go not away, the comforter will not
come unto you. But if I depart, I will
send him unto you.
>> Oh, so Jesus going to do the sending,
right?
>> Right.
>> Yes.
>> At the end of verse 7.
>> Skip down to verse read verse 12 to 15.
>> Okay. It says, "I have yet many things
to say unto you, but ye cannot bear them
now.
How be it, when he, the Spirit of truth,
is come, he will guide you into all
truth.
>> For he for he shall not speak of
himself, but whatsoever he shall hear,
that shall he speak, and he will show
you these things to come."
>> Uhhuh. He shall glorify me, for he shall
receive of mine, and shall show it unto
you.
>> Uhhuh.
>> All things that the father hath are
mine.
Therefore said, I
>> Mhm.
>> finish it.
>> That he shall take of mine and shall
show it unto you.
So now this comforter which is the Holy
Ghost here now now he is sent
and he going to take the words take
Jesus words and he's going to show it to
you and Jesus said all that the fathers
have
is mine. So that mean that Jesus got it
from the father. Father got it and and
and let's see what and uh uh let's see
what Jesus did with it. Let's go to one
last place. Revelation the first chapter
and we read verses 1 and two.
>> Okay.
Revelation 1 and one says the revelation
of Jesus Christ which gave which
>> one go ahead.
>> Yes sir. Which God gave unto him.
>> That's two. Didn't Jesus say all that
the father have is mine?
>> Yes. Yeah,
>> go ahead and read.
>> To show unto his servants things which
must shortly come to pass.
>> And he sent and signified it by his
angel
>> unto his servant John.
>> Oh, so you got a trinity there, don't
you?
>> God the Father, God the Son, and an
angel, which is a mining spirit. And
they are three individuals. They are not
one.
That's all I have to say.
>> All right. Thank you for that. As we
move on to our next question,
>> next one. Marcus Kimbro asks, "Are we
allowed to eat halal
clean for Muslims meat or eat at halal
restaurants?"
>> What you say, Dre?
>> Yeah. allow meat is just the way that
they go about to to slaughter their
animals and what is permissible because
that's what halal means permissible
permissible or lawful for Muslims.
However, in their law they eat shrimp.
So, we don't go by that law. We go by
the dietary law that is written in
Leviticus 11. So that's what we go by in
terms of the things that are clean
there. If you go to a restaurant that
serve those things that are clean, sure
you can eat it. That's all I got.
>> All right. Thank you for that, brother.
As we go on to our next question,
>> next one. NR asked in Deuteronomy 30:es
1-10
referring to those who are living when
Jesus come back but not caught up to
meet. Okay. Is Deuteronomy 30:es 1-10
referring to those who are living when
Jesus come back but not caught up to
meet believers in the first
resurrection.
All right, brother Jerome.
>> Yeah, let's um let's go read it. That
Deuteronomy 30 1-10
um is talking about those they're not
going to be in the first resurrection,
but they're going to be gathered from
all over the world, the children of
Israel primarily from all over the
world. And but they didn't make the
first resurrection and he going to bring
them to the wilderness. Okay. Uh but
let's go read it. Deuteronomy 30 verse1.
We ain't gonna read all those verses. We
gonna read I just point out some key
verses to establish the point. But go
ahead and start at that one. And it
shall come to pass when all these things
are come upon thee, the blessing and the
curse which I have set before thee, and
thou shalt call them to mind among all
the nations whether the Lord thy God has
driven thee.
Go ahead.
>> And shalt return unto the Lord thy God,
and shalt obey his voice, according to
all that I command thee this day, thou
and thy children, with all thine heart,
and with all thy soul.
>> Go ahead.
>> That then the Lord thy God will turn thy
captivity, and have compassion upon
thee, and will return, and gather thee
from all the nations, whether the Lord
thy God has scattered thee. Mhm.
>> If any of thine be driven out unto the
outmost parts of heaven, from thence
will the Lord thy God gather thee, and
from thence will he fetch thee.
>> So he scattered them among the nations,
and the nations is not where the father
and the son dwell. The nations are on
the earth. So the heaven in this verse
is actually the first heaven heaven
which is which the is the earth. Go
ahead and read. And the Lord thy God
will bring thee into the land which thy
fathers possessed, and thou shalt
possess it, and he will do thee good,
and multiply thee above thy fathers."
>> Okay, now pay attention to the sixth
verse. Go ahead.
>> And the Lord thy God will circumcise
thine heart, and the heart of thy seed,
to love the Lord thy God with all thine
heart, and with all thy soul, that thou
mayest live.
>> Yeah. And so he going to bring them
under the bond of the covenant. He going
to circumcise their heart. And the ones
that want to want their heart
circumcised, they going to obey the
Lord. The ones that ain't, the Lord
going to purge him in the wilderness.
That's that's actually in Ezekiel the
20th chapter 34 through 38. Okay? So
write that down. But go ahead.
and the Lord thy God will put all these
curses upon thine enemies, and on them
that hate thee, which persecuted thee.
Okay, so yeah, the the these uh uh flesh
and blood people that's going to be
gathered. No, they ain't going to be in
the first resurrection.
That's all I got.
>> All right. Thank you for that, brother
and sister.
>> De call.
>> Yeah, go ahead. Yes. Call
>> answer is simply yes.
Okay.
>> All right.
>> All right. All right. Sister Deborah, we
know we are at our time, but there's two
more short questions that we can
address. So, can you please um give us
um just a couple of more minutes and
let's read the next question.
>> Yeah. And then try to get at least one
for today. Ricky Oeen asks, "Can you
watch Bible movies and educational
videos on the Sabbath?"
>> All right. Can you watch Bible movies
and educational videos on the Sabbath
day?
And um
>> as long as they are the uncut word of
God.
>> Yep, sir. All right, we're gonna move on
to our next question.
>> Yes. Next one. And Neil Deng says,
"Please help me understand the baptism
with fire. Is it talking about Jesus
putting people in the lake of fire and
Matthew 3 verse 11 and 12 are given?"
>> Yes. Caller. Baptism with fire.
>> Read it.
>> Okay. Matthew 3 11 and 12 say, "I indeed
baptize you with water unto repentance,
but he that cometh after me is mightier
than I, whose shoes I am not worthy to
bear. And he shall baptize you with the
Holy Ghost and with fire,
whose fan is in his hand, and he will
thoroughly purge his floor and gather
his wheat unto the garner, but he will
burn up the chief with unquenchable
fire.
>> Now, the first thing is he going to
baptize you with the Holy Ghost. Let's
go, let's go into Mark the first chapter
and read verse 8.
Mark 1 and8 says, "I indeed have
baptized you with water, but he shall
baptize you with the Holy Ghost."
>> Now, this is the word. Uh let's go into
Acts 11 and read verses 11 and 16.
Acts
Acts 11 and verse
11- 16.
>> Okay. And it says, "And behold,
immediately there were three men already
come unto the house where I was, sent
from Cesaria unto me. and the Spirit
bade me go with them. Nothing doubting,
moreover, these six brethren accompanied
me, and we entered into the man's house.
And he showed us how he had seen an
angel in his house, which stood and said
unto him, "Send men to Japa, and call
for Simon, whose surname is Peter, who
shall tell thee words whereby thou, and
all thy house shall be saved." And as I
began to speak, the Holy Ghost fell on
them as on us at the beginning.
Then remembered Uhhuh.
>> Go ahead. Finish it.
>> Then remembered I the word of the Lord,
how that he said, John indeed baptized
with water, but ye shall be baptized
with the Holy Ghost.
Now in this case it's the word of God
but also
the 12th verse is talking about the lake
of fire. Let me show you what I'm
talking about. Read that the 12th verse
one more time.
>> Okay. The 12th verse says and the spirit
bade me go with them. Nothing doubting
more. No, no, no. I'm coming.
>> Matthew 3 verse 12.
>> I'm sorry. Matthew 3.
>> Matthew. Matthew 3:12 says, "Whose fan
is in his hand, and he will thoroughly
purge his floor and gather his wheat
into the garner, but he will burn up the
chief which un with unquenchable fire."
>> Now, that's talking about the lake of
fire. Go to Matthews 13 and read from
24-30. That'll be it.
13 vers Matthew 13 24-30
says
another parable put he forth unto them
saying the kingdom of heaven is likened
unto a man which seth good seed in his
field. But while men slept, his enemy
came and sold tears among the wheat and
went his way. But when the blade was
sprung up and brought forth fruit, then
appeared the t the tears also. So the
servants of the householder came and
said unto him, "Sir, did not thou sow
good seed unto thy field? From whence
then hath it tears?"
He said unto them, "An enemy has done
this." The servant said unto him, "Wilt
thou then that we go and gather them
up?" But he said, "Nay, least while ye
gather up the tears, ye root up also the
wheat with them.
Let both grow together unto the harvest.
And in the time of harvest, I will say
to the reapers, gather ye together first
the tears, and bind them in bundles to
burn them, but gather the wheat unto my
barn.
So it let you know ones that they put in
this bond, those are people that's going
to get saved and the tab you going to
burn in the lake of fire.
So the answer to that thing is it's both
of them. He going to baptize you with
the word first and then he and if that
don't work, he going to baptize you with
the liquor fire. That's all I have to
say.
>> All right. Thank you for that. Final
question of the evening, Deborah.
>> Uh yes, we are now into tonight's Q&A
for Wednesday, March the 4th, 2026.
Jister asks, "What is the time period
that takes place in Joel 2 verses 1-1?"
What is the time period for Joel 2 1-1?
>> Well, we're not going to read 1-1,
that's for sure. That's the final
question of the evening, Joel 2. And
let's go there. And as you pick it up at
1, we'll open it up to the panel. and uh
shorten it as we go along. But right
ahead, brother.
>> Okay. Joel 2:1 says, "Blow ye the
trumpet in Zion, and sound an alarm in
my holy mountain. Let all the
inhabitants of the land tremble, for the
day of the Lord cometh, for it is nigh
at hand."
>> The whole thing is all that is about the
coming of the Lord.
>> Yes, sir.
That's all it's about. That's the time
period. That's when it going west going
to go against the east and the east
going to go with the west and before the
east is going to be like before them
like the garden of Eden and behind them
is going to be waste and destruction.
That's when Russia and her allies going
to come across the Euphrates River. So
that time period all starts when the
heaven roll back like a scroll and Jesus
shows up.
>> Okay. Yep. All right. We want to thank
you and Sister Deborah. We have went
over our time, but we gave him a rare
treat this evening. And we want to thank
everybody from all around the world who
tuned in with us this evening. And we
want to say that if you have not been
able to join us for our black history,
coming up this Sabbath will be our final
part, which is part five, the adoption.
And this pertains to white, black, rich,
poor, young, and old. All can be a part
of the adoption. All you have to do is
just serve the God of Abraham, Isaac,
and Jacob. So, we want to say until we
all come together again, thank you. And
we say be safe, be blessed. May the Lord
have mercy on us all as we stay prayed
up. And brother James closes us out. Our
Father, which art in heaven, hallowed be
thy name. Thy kingdom come, thy will be
done in earth as it is in heaven. Give
us this day our daily bread, and forgive
us our debts as we forgive our debtors,
and lead us not into temptation, but
deliver us from evil. For thine is the
kingdom and the power and the glory
forever. In Jesus name we pray.